<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Adrienne Franke</title>
    <link>https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Adrienne Franke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 09:43:01 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021 Epochs &#43; Rewards</title>
      <link>https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/2021-epochs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 09:43:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/2021-epochs/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;m defining the weeks for next year. I decided on this because the weeks start on Mondays and end with a weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll have plenty of time to get ideas hashed out during the week and on the weekend, I can spend the days fine tuning and finishing them up. Completing a song will be a great way to end a weekend!
I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to keep this table up to date with my progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snippets from &#39;Here, There and Everywhere: My Life Recording the Music of The Beatles&#39; by Geoff Emerick</title>
      <link>https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/here-there-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 21:10:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/here-there-everywhere/</guid>
      <description>I read this book looking for inspiration from one of my favorite bands and their recording engineer, Geoff Emerick. Emerick&amp;rsquo;s responsible for the cutting edge, fantastic engineering on some of my favorite Beatles records: Revolver, Sgt Pepper, and Abbey Road. I highly recommend the book. It was an insightful page turner. Here are a few snippets that stuck with me as I read.
&amp;ldquo;It was because of those very limitations that we were put on the spot, forced to make creative decisions every step of the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Song a Week: Rules of the Game</title>
      <link>https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/the-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 17:15:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/the-rules/</guid>
      <description>I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to lay down some basic rules here. What will push me to be better and what will make it easier for me to accomplish this goal? I want a nice balance.
 The song must be recorded in some way, but it does not need to be mixed or mastered. The song should be at least 2 minutes long. Ideas, chord progressions, melodies, beats, lyrics, etc can be used even if they were written before 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Song a Week: Why?</title>
      <link>https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 17:12:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writingasongaweek.com/posts/why/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Don’t wait for inspiration. It comes while one is working.&amp;rdquo; ~Henri Matisse I can&amp;rsquo;t remember where or when I got the idea to write a song a week for an entire year, but it was sometime in November or December of this year. I was just about to finish my 2020 New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution (to read one book a month) and was starting to toss ideas around of what I could do in 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
